On my day off,
It has been raining since morning.
The circulator I've been waiting for arrived at noon.
I thought it would be convenient to have one in the changing room where there is no air conditioner.
and
It is rumored to save more electricity than an air conditioner.
Well, what do you think?
It's humid every day.
Candles, stuffed animals, matches...
If I put away the warm things.
I'm going to try to see if I can cool off just my mood.
Hydrangea with rain drops makes me think of a beautiful rainy day.
I found a blueberry tree at a flower shop.
Do these berries turn blue? I asked.
Oh no... how about that? 😅
and I made the florist laugh lol.
(Don't ask anything that comes to mind)
It's raining and I'm too lazy to go out.
I got up late in the morning, went to the local florist and the supermarket.
And when I was doing that
I realized it was past noon.
The day started slowly,
The day off goes by very quickly.
I accidentally caught a cold and
I took antibiotics for a week.
I've had sinusitis a couple of times, and I've had facial pain.
This time it was a headache.
I was told to take an antibiotic and see what happens.
I got better in a few days, but
I had completely forgotten how hard a cold can be. lol
I bought a beer today to celebrate my recovery.🍺
I also bought some delicious new potatoes to make snacks.
I couldn't pass by the delicious looking corn either, so I add one more dish  to the list.
In the rainy season, the food I want to eat is appearing every time I go to the supermarket,
It's also a happy busy season!
In the recipe, it's red chili.
but I'm going to use green chili peppers that are starting to wrinkle in the fridge.
Bongole pasta added in a hurry.
I completely forgot to use the clams I bought at half price last night.
Heat 2 tablespoons of white wine until it opens.
In the season of many delicious foods, it is easy to inadvertently increase the number of dishes.
Boiled potatoes with 10 grams of butter.
25g potato starch, salt and pepper.
(I was going to make a lot of these and freeze them, but I failed to fry them and couldn't make stock.)
I should have dusted the cutting board well with potato starch because it tends to stick.
When I fry them, the dough expands and the face disappears.
It is better to make a hole sharply .
And then I dust the corn with 1/2 tablespoon of flour and a pinch of salt.
1 1/2 tablespoons each of flour and potato starch, 2 1/2 tablespoons water
Check the temperature of the oil with chopsticks and fry.
This first one somehow failed because it melted.
I re-molded the leftover dough and tried again.
The corn slowly goes into the oil.
Fry it without touching it until it's nice and crunchy.
Add some green seaweed and black pepper.
With beer for a get well celebration,
Lifting the ban on rich food.
Cooking on a mushy day makes more delicious beer.
I'm not good at alcohol very much.
but I can drink one glass without worry.
All the recipes were satisfying and tasty, perfect for a get well celebration.🤤
I tend to accumulate laundry on rainy days somehow.
I can't let it accumulate forever, so just do it.
And one more thing that I've been neglecting...
I saved the filter and cut it smaller, and it was dusty around the edges.
This time I cover it well.
I don't know why it's so dusty... 😓
Is there a smell specific to this time of year?
I'm always wondering what would be a good scent for my room.
This time I'm going to try paper incense.
(After this, the fragrance still lingered for two days)
I wanted to buy something and decided to go out quickly.
They say I can put paper incense in  bag, in  business card case, etc.
Try tucking it into a handkerchief.
It's raining, but I wanted to go out in my easy sandals.
I'm going to wear them with waterproof spray.
It smells soft and nice and soothing.
Tokyo station has a lot of underground area.
It's nice to be able to go to various places without getting wet in the rain.
I'm going to explore without going above ground.
I'll take a souvenir for my sister who loves pasta.
Chocolate chip ice cream.
It tastes so good and nostalgic!
And I got what I wanted, too.
I wondered if I should walk outside too.
but I still turned back to the basement and went home.🚃☔
In this season when there are so many foods to eat in the supermarket,
I have to cook as much as I can to make it in time.
These are prickly peppercorns that I bought before I caught a cold.
I had to take care of them as soon as I bought them,
It turned black in some places.
While removing the overly blackened berries,
I'm going to remove the berries from the thick branches.
I thought it would be quick, but it took longer than I thought, and the water boiled first.
I boil it for 4 to 5 minutes until it's soft.
Soak in water for about an hour to remove scum.
Put it between chopsticks.
Halfway through, make a diagonal slit
The other half side, make a straight incision.
Sprinkle salt on it.
1 1/2 teaspoons each of soy sauce, bean-paste, sugar, sesame oil, vinegar
(I used sweet chili sauce instead of soy sauce)
The lemon-patterned thing under the cutting board is a mat for children to use when they eat.
I don't know if I can use it like this,
but it's very convenient because it can be washed quickly and it doesn't slip.
Thinly sliced meat with lots of lettuce and myoga.
Hokkaido asparagus is only available at this time in June!
(This is a tidbit from a calendar.🤫)
The bitterness of the shishito pepper is a nice accent to the grilled skewers.
I'm going to prepare various kinds of skewers together.
I am regretting that I should have added some bell peppers that I have in the fridge.
Green onions and minced chicken
1 teaspoon sake, soy sauce, ginger
1 medium spoonful of potato starch
Fillet of mackerel
Horse mackerel in season wrapped with shiso leaves and skewered
1 tablespoon sake, soy sauce, mirin, 2 teaspoons sugar
I didn't have any salt to sprinkle.
Grate rock salt with a cheese grater...
ume syrup with soda
Eat a bellows cucumber before baking.
I'm going to eat one peppercorn.
It's fresh and goes well with the marbled white meat.
Ume plum and wasabi on top.
Grill, drink, eat and be busy.
Tsukune with fresh green pepper.
Fish skewers are also really good.🐟
Rummaging through the fridge to find something to eat for night snack.
I open what I bought.
Fruit soda and cookies for a snack.
Just walking outside, it's damp all over body.
I even think that alone is exhausting.😂
I went to buy body powder for the first time.
I was also recommended a body spray that feels cool.
I was so damp that I wanted to take a shower as soon as possible.
I couldn't help but buy it.
It has a refreshing herbal fragrance.
I think it will heal the unpleasant smell of the rainy season.
Body Powder
I bought one with a puff.
I wanted to apply it all over my body, so I could have gotten myself a bigger one.
I'd like to believe it's a good purchase if it makes the dreary rainy season a little easier.😂
Do you have a song that sometimes pops into your head and you want to listen to it again?
I'm breaking up a grilled chicken that I've just skewered.
A common debate about whether to remove the skewer from a grilled chicken.
I've finally come to my own conclusion.
(It's very vain to remove something I've gone to the trouble of skewering.😂)
While making sure to keep the fire going, at the same time
Water, broth, soy sauce, and salt as needed
Pushing the limits of the egg cooker...
A busy morning of cooking and cleaning up
Now I'm ready for even dinner
I bought some pickled daikon radish a while ago.
I'm wearing a white blouse for lighten my mind
A black skirt that I don't have to worry about stains
I'll take the mini-bottle that comes with it
On rainy days, the rain doesn't seep inside.
Longchamp bags are very useful.
I bought my first pair of cold stockings.
It doesn't make me feel cooler,
but it feels cooler a little.
I like folding umbrellas in a plastic bag.😂
Thank you for watching to the end!